ALEXANDER CAPPELEN

Sociology | Social Data Science | cand.scient.soc

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Department of Social Data Science, University of Copenhagen

🛗 January 2023 - December 2023

- **♀** Copenhagen
- Teaching methods of social data science, digital methods, and providing guidance in student projects
- Teaching machine learning, network analysis, and causal inference, including application with Python

Student Assistant

Department of Sociology, University of Copenhagen

April 2022 - September 2022

- **♀** Copenhagen
- Contributed in developing survey and gathering contact information for survey participants
- Collected data on book loans from public libraries in Denmark through an API using Python

Student Assistant

Department of Economics, Copenhagen Business School

Movember 2020 - October 2021

- Reviewing data and code for errors
- Aiding in litterature review for researchers

RELEVANT COURSES

Thesis: Parlarchy in the UK Department of Sociology

- GIS, mapping data, and spatial panel regression
- Analysis of behavioral data from social media
- Conceptualising far right social movements on alternative social media

S&DS 565: Introductory Machine Learning Department of Statistics and Data Science, Yale University

Fall 2022

- Supervised learning, unsupervised learning, linear regression, classification, stochastic gradient descent, cross validation, tree-based methods, topic models, language models, word embeddings, Bayesian inference, neural networks
- pandas, numpy, matplotlib, tensorflow, scikit-learn, seaborn, Jupyter Notebook

S&DS: Data Science for Political Campaigns
Department of Statistics and Data Science, Yale University

CONTACT

@ alexander.cappelen@hotmail.com

4 +45 27 46 01 08

alexpcapp

24.11.1995

IT

R Python LaTeX STATA HTML & CSS SOL



LANGUAGES

Danish English



EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Sociology

University of Copenhagen

🛗 Sept 2021 - January 2024

Exchange student

Yale University

🗎 Sept 2022 - December 2022

B.Sc. in Sociology University of Copenhagen

B.Sc. in Technoanthropology (not finished)

University of Aalborg

Sept 2017 - June 2018 (dropped out)

- Modelling of voter behavior, evaluating campaigns, voter experiments
- pandas, numpy, matplotlib, Jupyter Notebook

Independent study

Department of Sociology, Yale University

Fall 2022

- Writing (short) paper intended for publication in collaboration with an adviser
- Analysing and mapping data from social media using R

Econometrics I

Department of Economics, University of Copenhagen

Fall 2020

 Causal inference, regression analysis, natural experiments, time series, DiD

The Logic of Design-Based Research

Department of Sociology, University of Copenhagen

₩ Fall 2021

- Causal inference, IV, DiD, regression discontinuity, experiments & natural experiments
- Counterfactual model of causality

Advanced Knowledge, Organization, Politics Department of Sociology, University of Copenhagen

₩ Fall 2021

 Applying social network analysis of Danish politics on Twitter for final paper

AWARDS

Award for Best Bachelor's Thesis 2022 from the Society for Survey Research

Spring 2022

• Press here for more info

ABOUT ME

For almost two decades, I have spent a lot of my time playing volleyball and beachvolleyball, at one point on the highest level in Denmark. I still play multiple times a week, although at a more casual level now. Besides many friendships and great experiences, I believe my background in team sports have contributed greatly to my ability to productively cooperate with others - handle criticism well, take responsibility, be accountable, and participate productively in teamwork.

When I am not spending time on sports, I enjoy making use of Copenhagen for both cultural experiences, food, and drinks. Especially in the summer, I take pleasure in the parks, swimming in the canals, and generally being out and about in the city with friends and family.